Mark Yu

Full stack programmer coming from a DevOps background, looking to focus more on software development, with 3 years of professional experience developing containerized backend services, and with casual, self-motivated frontend projects in Javascript, React, Redux, Android, and Firebase.

(217) 381-2798 zyu.atwork@gmail.com markzyu.netlify.app

EXPERIENCE

Facebook, Menlo Park, CA — Production Engineer (DevOps)

May 2017 - Aug 2017, July 2018 - May 2021

- Promoted within a three-month timeframe from intern to full time.
- Cooperated on and rolled out a containerized Back-End Service and a Front-End User Interface that allocate and enforce machine resource quotas. Negotiated quotas and enforcement policies with 10+ teams and customers. Improved the utilization of machines and resources.
- Troubleshooted and debugged an old Python automation, resolved design flaws and rewrote the program to free up ~150TB of disk space in every major data center, every 3 months, to run 2.9 times faster than the old version, run as a service in a Twine container, and use less RAM.
- Performed 15+ remote onsite interviews, and evaluated candidates based on their knowledge of Linux System Architecture.
- Implemented a Python script that performed Scuba queries and discovered ~500 unused GPU servers, and prevented the idle waste of company assets worth at least \$500,000.
- Followed the instruction of my internship mentor to implement a
 Python service that gathers and analyzes the errors from log output of
 user applications that run on our infrastructure.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois, Urbana, IL — Computer Science, B.S.

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Assisted with research on a Linux Kernel plugin, and a Machine Learning experiment. Graduated with Highest Honors and GPA: 3.95 out of 4.0

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Twitch streamer's helper app — *Javascript*, HTML, Python

It discreetly notifies a streamer about stream quality, chats, and new followers, in real time, and has proven useful in 110+ Twitch streams.

 ${\bf Barcode\ phone\ app-\it Typescript,\it React\ Native,\it Android}$

It scans barcodes and builds a database of my belongings.

Password manager app — Javascript, React, Redux, Jest

It has 35 test cases for 1 webpage, and doesn't store the password directly.

Note-taking app — *Javascript*, *React*, *Firebase*

It enabled multiple users to edit or view documents in Firebase databases.

SKILLS

Javascript/Node.js (hobby)

React/Redux, Jest (hobby)

React Native, Android (hobby)

Firebase/AWS DocDB (hobby)

Java (hobby)

C++/Rust/Golang (hobby)

Python

Git/Mercurial

Thrift/gRPC

Twine/Docker

Scuba/Presto SQL queries

Linux System Architecture

LANGUAGES

English

Chinese